Guide to the Records of the New York Foundling Hospital 1869-2009 MS 347
New-York Historical Society
- Series I - Minutes of the Board of Trustees/Managers, and Related Materials, 1869-1978
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1954-1956 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1957 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers and Correspondence to Administrator Sister Marie Catherine, 1958 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers and Correspondence from Administrator to Mother Mary of Sisters of Charity, 1959 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1960 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1961 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1962 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1963 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1964 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1965 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1966 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1967 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1968 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1969 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1970 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1971 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1972 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1973 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1974 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Director's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1975 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
  - Executive Director's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1976 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
  - Executive Director's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1977 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
  - Executive Director's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1978 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers, 1957 August-1968 December (Offsite-box 79, Volume 12)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Managers/Trustees, 1972 March-1975 December (Offsite-box 79, Volume 13)
  - Administrator's Reports to the Board of Trustees, 1976 March-1978 December (Offsite-box 79, Volume 14)
- Series II - Annual Reports and Inspections, 1869-2000
  This series consists of 3 subseries:
  II.1 Published Biennial/Annual Reports 1869-2000
  II.2 Internal Annual Reports 1934-1981
  II.3 Biennial/Annual Inspections/Reports for State and Other Agencies, 1900-1953
  Please see Series IV.6 for annual reports of the Boarding Department.
  - Subseries II.1 - Published Annual and Biennial Reports, 1869-2000
    The subseries contains an incomplete set of reports distributed to the public and potential donors. There are multiple copies of many reports, including bound copies 1869-1917 and individual copies 1885-2000. There are some gaps, including no reports 1936-1943 or 1948-1961 (see Series VII.2 to fill in gaps 1958-1962). Bound copies are arranged first, followed by individual copies.
    Annual Reports from 1958-1966 were published as the March issue of Mater Dei, a monthly publication of the Foundling. This series includes loose copies of the annual report issues of Mater Dei from 1963-1965. Bound copies of the periodical, which include annual reports 1958-1962 not represented in this subseries, may be found in Series VII.2 - Newsletters.
    - Biennial Reports, 1870-1883 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 15)
    - Biennial Reports (pages missing), 1871-1883 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 16)
    - Biennial/Annual Reports, 1870-1884 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 17)
    - Biennial Reports, 1884-1895 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 18)
    - Biennial Reports, 1894-1905 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 19)
    - Biennial Reports, 1906-1917 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 20)
    - Annual Report (1 copy), 1885 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
    - Biennial Report (1 copy), 1890-1891 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
    - Biennial Report (3 copies), 1896-1897 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
    - Biennial Report (2 copies), 1898-1899 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
    - Biennial Report (3 copies), 1900-1901 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
    - Biennial Report (2 copies), 1900-1901 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
    - Biennial Report (3 copies), 1902-1903 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
    - Biennial Report (1 copy), 1904-1905 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 8)
    - Biennial Report (3 copies), 1908-1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
    - Biennial Report (1 copy), 1916-1917 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
    - Biennial Report (1 copy), 1918-1919 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
    - Biennial Report (1 copy), 1920-1921 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
    - Biennial Report (2 copies), 1922-1923 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
    - Biennial Report (2 copies), 1924-1925 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
    - Biennial Report (5 copies), 1926-1927 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
    - Quadrennial Report (4 copies, folder 1 of 2), 1928-1931 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
    - Quadrennial Report (4 copies, folder 2 of 2), 1928-1931 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
    - Biennial Report (4 copies), 1932-1933 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
    - Biennial Report (5 copies), 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1944 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report Pamphlet, circa 1947 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1962 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report 1963 and Summary Report 1958-1963, published as Mater Dei Vol. 9, Nos. 10 and 11 (2 copies), 1964 February-March (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report 1964, published as Mater Dei Vol. 10, Nos. 10 and 11 (1 copy), 1965 February-March (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report 1965, published as Mater Dei Vol. 11, Nos. 10 and 11 (3 copies), 1966 February-March (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1967 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1969 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1970 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
    - Annual Report (1 copy), 1971 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
    - Annual Report (1 copy), 1972 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
    - Annual Report (1 copy), 1974 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1975 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
    - Annual Report (4 copies), 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 15)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1979 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 16)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1980 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 17)
    - Annual Report (4 copies), 1981 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 18)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1982 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 19)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1983 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 20)
    - Annual Report (4 copies), 1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 21)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1986 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 22)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1989 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1990 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report (2 copies), 1991 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1992 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1993 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1994 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1997 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 1999 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
    - Annual Report (3 copies), 2000 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II.2 - Internal Annual Reports, 1934-1981
    The subseries consists of annual reports of all departments at the Foundling bound together with introductory notes 1934-1972. 1938-1945 are missing, except for a disbound and shorter internal annual report from 1942; there are also gaps from 1949-1963 and 1970-1971.
    These internal annual reports tend to contain more statistical information than the published annual reports in the previous subseries. This subseries concludes with one folder containing miscellaneous departmental annual reports 1977 and 1981. The miscellaneous reports were prepared by departments not represented elsewhere in the collection.
    For separate reports by other departments, see Series IV.
    - Internal Annual Report, 1934 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 10)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1935 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 11)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1936 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 12)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1936-1937 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 13)
    - Internal Annual Report (disbound), 1942 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 14)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1946 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 15)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1947 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 16)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1948 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 17)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1949 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1950 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1951 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1952 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1953 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1954 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1955 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1956 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1957 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1958 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1959 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1961 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1963 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1964 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1965 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1966 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1967 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1968 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1969 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
    - Internal Annual Report, 1972 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Departmental Annual Reports, 1977, 1981 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
  - Subseries II.3 - Annual/Biennial Inspections/Reports for State and Other Agencies, 1900-1953
    The subseries consists mainly of annual inspections of the Foundling by the State Board of Charities, renamed the State Department of Social Welfare in 1930. These are followed by annual reports to other organizations.
    The State Board of Charities performed annual or biannual inspections of the Foundling beginning in 1900. This New York State government department changed its name to the State Department of Social Welfare in 1930. The subseries contains inspections by the state agencies of the Foundling's Infant Asylum 1900-1928, the Foundling's hospitals 1900-1910 and 1930-1944, the Foundling's Placing-Out and Boarding-Out Departments 1901-1935, the Foundling as a whole in 1944 and 1951, as well as annual reports by the Foundling to the State Department of Social Welfare 1937-1951.
    The subseries concludes with three other annual reports: an annual report of the Section on Care of Dependent Children to the Welfare Council of New York City (an association of social service agencies including the Foundling), 1936; and 2 annual reports of the Foundling to the Roman Catholic Orphan Asylum (1952 and 1953). Note that Series IV.5 - Boarding Department - also includes annual reports of that department prepared for the Roman Catholic Orphan Asylum.
    For State Department of Social Welfare/Board of Charities inspections of the St. Joseph's-by-The-Sea facility, see Series IV.38 - St. Joseph's-by-The-Sea.
    - State Board of Charities - Infant Asylum Inspections, 1900-1907 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    - State Board of Charities - Infant Asylum Inspections, 1908-1913 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    - State Board of Charities - Infant Asylum Inspections, 1915-1918 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
    - State Board of Charities - Infant Asylum Inspections, 1919-1928 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    - State Board of Charities - Hospital Inspections, 1900-1910 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    - State Department of Social Welfare - Hospital Inspections, 1930-1944 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
    - State Board of Charities - Placing-Out/Boarding-Out Department Inspections, 1901-1912 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
    - State Board of Charities - Placing-Out/Boarding-Out Department Inspections, 1913-1917 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    - State Board of Charities - Placing-Out/Boarding-Out Department Inspections, 1918-1927 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    - State Board of Charities/Dept. of Social Welfare - Placing-Out Department Inspections, 1929-1932 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
    - State Department of Social Welfare - Boarding-Out Department Inspections and Related Materials, 1927-1932 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
    - State Department of Social Welfare - Inspection and Related Materials, 1932-1935 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
    - Reports to State Department of Social Welfare, 1937-1945 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    - State Department of Social Welfare Survey of Foundling and Related Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    - State Department of Social Welfare Survey of the Foundling, with Annual Statistics Appendices, and related correspondence, 1951-1952 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
    - Annual Report of the Section on Care of Dependent Children to Welfare Council of N.Y.C., circa 1936 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
    - Annual Reports to the Roman Catholic Orphan Asylum, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
- Series III - Administrative Records, Chronological, 1869-2004
  This series contains a variety of different types of records, including the Foundling's constitution and by-laws and revisions to these, a small amount of selected correspondence, reports, policy manuals, grant proposals, strategic plans, and legal documents, arranged in chronological order. Many records relate to the purchase, construction, or maintenance of real estate.
  The records most often concern the institution as a whole, as opposed to individual programs or departments of the Foundling. Records of individual centers, programs, and departments are arranged as Series IV.
  - Charter, Constitution, Revisions, By-Laws and other documents - Sisters of Charity copies, 1869-1910 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Donation correspondence addressed to Sister Irene, 1869 October 4 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Incorporation - photocopy and photostat, 1869 October 9 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
  - Petition to the state for funds for new building - photostat, circa 1869 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
  - Constitution and By-Laws - photostats, circa 1870 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lease of 68th Street property - handwritten copy, 1870 December 15 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
  - Document re: payment by city to Foundling for building construction, 1871 March (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
  - Declaration and By-Laws of the Advisory Committee of the Foundling, 1874 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
  - Petition to the state to permit erection of buildings, 1874 March 24 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
  - Petition to governor to sign bill for increased funds for Foundling, and copy of bill, and copy of final act, and comments from 1894 and 1992, 1874 March 10 - 1874 June 30, 1894, 1992 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
  - Act authorizing state payments to Foundling, 1877 March 15 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1886-1935 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and other documents re: property at 223 E. 67th St., 1888 and 1916-1922 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
  - Receipts for rent paid by Foundling to city - photostats, 1889-1941 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
  - Seton and Nazareth Hospitals, Spuyten Duyvil - Correspondence, By-Laws, and other documents, 1890-1899 and undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
  - Title change documents, 1891 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with State Board of Charities, and related documents, 1893-1922 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Con Edison and other electric companies. Oversize blueprint of 68th Street property separated to Box OS1, Folder 1, 1897-1988 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous reports, invoices, correspondence, lists and other documents, 1898-1922 and undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Chief Examiner of Accounts of Institutions to Comptroller Edward Grout arguing for Foundling records' secrecy - copy, 1903 April 20 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with Chicago Dept. of Education re: children placed in Chicago, 1905 June 27 and July 1 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 21)
  - Conference on Dependent Children - report and related correspondence, 1909 January 30 and March (Offsite-box 13, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence related to Kingsbury issue, copies glued into volume, 1909 January 30, and 1917 February 27-May 18 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and reports related to demand by John A. Kingsbury, Commissioner of N.Y.C. Dept. of Public Charities, that Foundling provide information on families of children in their care, 1910 October 11 and 1917 January 5-October 11 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 24)
  - Appeal (transcript with pages missing, and photocopy), circa 1910 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions, 1911-1917 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous reports, and 2 newsletters, by Catholic Charities, 1911-1935 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and legal documents of the Foundling, copies glued into a volume, 1915 July 8 - 1917 December 26 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets relating to Strong Commission and Kingsbury controversy, 1916 February and June, and undated (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Department of Public Charities Report of Inspection of the Foundling, 1916 November 21 - December 13 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
  - By-Laws of the Foundling, revised to August 1917, 1917 August (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and legal documents of the Foundling, copies glued into a volume, 1918 January 17 - 1920 September 7 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
  - Administrative and legal correspondence of the Foundling, copies glued into a volume, 1921 February 25 - 1922 May 18 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with American College of Surgeons regarding surveys of hospitals, hospital standardization, conferences, 1921 April - 1946 March (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and other documents regarding property at 164 and 175 E. 68th Street, 1921 November - 1959 March (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, resolutions, architectural studies and other documents related to purchase and sale of 68th Street property, 1921, 1942-1946, 1953-1958 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and other materials related to Extension of Purpose, 1926 December - 1927 November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Extension and Change of Powers and Purposes, 1927 May 23 - 1927 June 27 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous administrative correspondence and other documents, 1930-1969 and undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - By-Laws, 1934 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Inspection of Foundling - Report to the Council on Medical Education and Hospitals of the American Medical Association, 1936 September 17 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and report of N.Y.C. Comptroller to Board of Estimate re: hospital overcrowding and recommendation to increase funding, 1940 February 7 and 19 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and legal documents related to purchase of property 68-69th Streets, 1944 April 19 - 1954 April 12 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
  - Report on Foundling by Department of Health and subsequent correspondence, 1944 May-November (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
  - Memo from Sister Carmela Therese, NY Foundling, to Sister Mary Berchmans, Mt. St. Vincent, and attachments relating chronology of Foundling administrative events 1944 October 2 - 1944 December 29, 1945 April 2 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
  - Citations awarded to Foundling for war bond sales, 1945 July 7 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notification of discontinuation of Hospital Division - copies, 1946 February 13 and March 4 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Report, 1947 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1946-1953 and circa 1950's (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
  - Photostat enlargements of correspondence from President Harry Truman regarding donation, 1949 March 28-April 2 (Offsite-box OS 1, Folder 2)
  - Lullaby Cottage Fundraising Project, 1949 April 13 - 1950 May 17 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
  - Letter to Cardinal Spellman signed by Eddie Cantor, 1949 November 10 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 14)
  - 1949 Statement, circa 1949 December (Offsite-box 15, Folder 15)
  - Departmental Policies, circa 1949 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 16)
  - By-Laws booklet, 1950 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 17)
  - Certificate of Report of Existence, 1950 December 12 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and contracts regarding purchase of property 1175 Third Avenue, 1954 March 30 - 1957 December 20 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 19)
  - Construction agreements and floorplans 1175 Third Avenue, 1956 April 2 - 1958 November 23 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 20)
  - Comments by Foundling administrator on plans for convent floor refectory, 1175 Third Avenue, circa 1956-1958 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and notes for cornerstone ceremony, 1175 Third Avenue, 1957 June 27 and July 3 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 22)
  - Publicity materials for move to new building (photocopies), 1958 September 2 - October (Offsite-box 15, Folder 23)
  - Program, press releases, transcriptions from dedication ceremony, 1175 Third Avenue, 1958 November 23 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous administrative correspondence, 1958-1964 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Rt. Rev. George A. Kelly regarding royalties from Catholic Marriage Manual, 1958-1979 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 26)
  - Information about Foundling departments (photocopy), circa 1958 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 27)
  - Blank Foundling letterhead stationery, circa 1958-1988 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 28)
  - Certificate of Occupancy, Foundling buildings, 1959 August 24 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 29)
  - Administrative Organization Chart (oversize), 1960 October 11 (Offsite-box OS 1, Folder 3)
  - Plant operation annual report, 1960 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence with State Department of Social Welfare, 1961-1965 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 31)
  - Copy of letter from Monsignor McGuire to Jacqueline Kennedy and reply from Letitia Baldridge, 1963 January 18 and 28 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Administrative Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 33)
  - Organization Manual, 1970-1973 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 21)
  - Manual of Policies and Procedures, 1971-1978 (Offsite-box 80, Volume 22)
  - Amendment to Certificate of Incorporation and Revised By-Laws, 1972-1974 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 34)
  - Certificate of Amendment of the Certificate of Incorporation and Restated Certificate of Incorporation, 1973 June 18 - 1975 October 10 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Brooke Astor resignation from Foundling board (photocopies), 1973 July 12 and 25 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - State Department of Social Services, 1973 September - 1978 January (Offsite-box 15, Folder 37)
  - List of Administrators, 1974 October (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)